hey all right welcome everyone this is
wasabi research club number 16 maybe and
today we are going to talk about
something that we started researching
and this will be different research club
from everything as was before because
from now on we are not going to review
papers but we are going to actually
research so this will become a research
club and not a review club and we will
get back reviewing papers as soon as we
stop researching and here we have today
East one and you are who are working
with me right now
wabi-sabi which is trustless which is
where we are trying to achieve
translation orbit rare coin joints and
why is it important what what's the
logic behind it if you have ever used
Cohen joins before at least with wasabi
then you might have noticed that you
have a lot of change and you cannot
actually send money in the Cohen joins
to other people and these are the
problems that we are trying to solve and
for that we first have to very quickly
go through how coin joints are being
done in in in a design level in
architecture level and it all comes down
to three main phases which is input
registration every user comes together
and register their inputs then output
registration
users register their desired outputs and
then finally coin join is built and
everyone has to sign and why this is
important is because this grantee is
security so if you don't see your design
desire the input a desired output in the
coin join them you don't sign your
output you don't sign the coin join so
the coin join will be invalid and it
won't be not happen so this is why you
cannot lose money in coin joins now
going further think about how to how to
register inputs and outputs to the coin
join in an anonymous way because these
input registrations should not be
connected together with each other
needed output registrations and for that
there are actually two school of
thoughts one is the coin shuffle school
of thought when they build their own
anonymity network to make sure the
anonymity is ensured within the
anonymity set which is all the users of
that coin join in asabi it's different
because there we are leveraging an
existing anonymity network called the
Tor network where the body it could be
any any other anonymity network where
every input registration and every
output registration must happen with
different anonymity network identities
so no one can figure out what's the link
there
however this brings up a great problem
here because if you can register outputs
to a Co enjoying anonymously then what
would prevent you from registering
as many on who says you like I mean it's
anonymous and that's what we are trying
to find the solution to how to register
arbitrary amount of inputs and arbitrary
how to register inputs with arbitrary
amounts and outputs with arbitrary
outputs
arbitrary amount and it's important the
arbitrary part is important here because
an an arbitrary way to register an an
arbitrary way to to prevent denial of
service attacks like registering many
outputs would be what wasabi bullet is
doing right now
is that you have to have some
denominations there and that way with
some blind signature magic which we will
go into later then we could make sure
there are no denial of service attacks
however if the amounts are arbitrary
then this was scheme doesn't work any
more because we have to the new question
becomes how to answer user does not
register more money in output
registration then he provided inputs for
but without knowing that which user
registered which inputs and which
outputs so the link should not be there
the link should not be there between
input and input registration of users
and output and output registration of
users and input and output registration
of users so that's what we are trying to
solve at the first phase of this
research work
it's a Patterson commitment scheme which
I think I'm going to give over the
explanation to you would you like to
explain
but but what was our very first way of
thinking which we only saw the splitting
of inputs at that point could you
explain that okay so first I did want to
add to your introduction that for now
we're not yet thinking about the
structure of the transaction how it ends
up so that's like out of scope for
today's discussion but it's still very
much a concern so anyway with that out
of the way I don't actually exactly
remember what signature scheme we wanted
to use but the idea of a Pettersen
commitment is if you have an elliptic
curve or any sort of group where the
discrete log assumption hardness
assumption holds you can take two points
on the curve called generators and
typically in pettersen commitments those
are called H and G and you can multiply
these two points by two numbers so one
of those would be the the actual message
and the other would be randomness and
this creates and then you can sum those
two values together and this is
something that is somewhat analogous to
a hash with salt or maybe an H Mac but
the idea is like you because you because
the discrete log problem is hard it's it
should be impossible for anybody to
figure out what values did you multiply
so what were your numbers that went into
this thing but then if you publish the
the sum of these two products then
you can later prove with which values
like you actually multiplied those
generators and the reason that you have
two of these so if you only multiply a
single generator by a number I believe
that's what's called a Patterson hash
and the idea is that like if the
messages are like kind of easy to guess
then having an additional randomness
term makes it like impossible to
brute-force that as well and the key
difference to sort of keep in mind for
the purpose of this discussion is that
unlike traditional hash functions
because the the group operation the
addition of points on the curve is
commutative this means that you have
like it doesn't matter in which order
you do this and the sum of the messages
going into this kind of hash function if
you take the the sum of several
Patterson commitments then what you get
back out is a Patterson commitment to
the sum of the messages which is a very
useful property I guess back to you
thank you I will risk sounding stupid
and I try to explain it again
in some less technical terms so how we
imagined to solve this issue of unlink
ability between inputs and outputs would
be that we figured if we if we have
let's say one Bitcoin and we want to get
an get output 0.1 and 0.9 bitcoins then
we create two feathers and commitments
more because there are zeros but let's
just not care about that we create two
patters and commitments for 0.1 and 0.9
and that input registration we prove
that that these stupid heirs and
commitment dee-dee-dee-dee sum is one
Bitcoin that our input and also have
some range proofs there but again that
that's a detail at this point and and we
also found blind Patterson commitment
scheme which enables us to get a blind
signature for the message of the paddles
and commitment without the the the
coordinator knowing the the actual
values there so give back the blank
signatures for the users and now the
users have unblind to signatures and the
users have two signatures for 40.1
Bitcoin and 0.9 Bitcoin and at output
registration it can come with two
different anonymity Network identity and
for once it registers the 0.1 Bitcoin
and provides the unblinded signature and
for twice it registers the 0.9 Bitcoin
this way the coordinator can not tell
because it has never seen these
signatures before it cannot which input
its
mind those those values for and that
that that was the basic working idea
that we had however if you think about
it it does not enable consolidating
input so if I have five inputs and I
want to make only one output of that
then I cannot do it with this scheme so
for this we figured out East Van figured
out that it could be possible with the
BLS blind BLS signature protocol and I
would like to give the words to East Van
could you explain the blind BLS
signature protocol that we figured out
and by the way this is not our our
state-of-the-art idea but it is it is
good to mention because it it works but
it's quite complex state of the art from
last week yes but we killed it really
badly maybe I don't know if you can
share your screen or I should but maybe
it would be helpful for everyone if we
can have a look at the github issue but
if not then like so okay please share
your square screen but I cannot share it
because it does not get recorded but if
anyone has shares it it gets recorded
yes
so like or the you well-motivated and
also on opera why we like Patterson
commitments so the thing is that in this
wabi-sabi protocol we need to prove
statements in zero knowledge about about
input u TX oh well used
so whenever for example a user registers
and impose Duty EXO and she would like
to register another or split this amount
into two let's say to a change address
or a payment value then we we need to
allow
users to create feathers and commitment
and prove that the patters and
commitments are formed in a good way
so meaning that the underlying
commitment values add up to the impute
EXO value so and with feathers and
commitments we can do as already no para
and you have described that we can
really easily prove such summation
statements over committed values and
then okay
the next idea was we love feathers and
commitments but because they are
homomorphic and they allow us to build
and prove easily this summing summation
statements then let's let's go with
another really flexible signature scheme
namely BLS which is kind of the most the
simplest signature scheme you can ever
imagine
so this is basically the BLS signature
scheme you can see here no this is sorry
the blind bill is signature scheme which
is still pretty simple so there's a
binding phase we have a message m we can
blind it
so we first of all we hash the message
and with the generator in the elliptic
curve group we can blind it with the
randomness R so we sent the blinded
message to the signer which in the
wasabi lingo or in the coin join the
feature we would call the coordinator so
the coordinator gets blinded message and
hat let's say and then the coordinator
can come blind it with his secret key
and then the receiver no sorry the
coordinator can sign this blinded
message and then the receiver um blinds
it so this is a three more signature
scheme and the big question was like
here we see a hash function right and
you've already pointed out this Paterson
hash we we all love because of its
homomorphic properties so one question
we needed to answer what
what should be this hash function and
let's let let's pick now the Patterson
hash because it preserves the algebraic
structure of the message so instead if
we would choose if we would go with a
hash function which like shatter shatter
e-cat sack then it would completely mess
up the structure of the message so it
would have would be really difficult so
not trivial at all how to prove
statements between these blinded
messages and yeah so shall I just easily
and quickly let me just first explain
like the impress registration phase so
we have a public value let's let's just
take this example we have a public value
M which which you can you should think
of em as as a subtle sheet amount which
is the subtle amount of your input
registered input and then you would like
to split this M your input to TXO into
two output you TXO values but you don't
want to reveal them to the coordinator
so you want to create you want to split
it into M 1 and M 2 and additionally you
want to prove to the coordinator that
the sum of M 1 and M 2 adds up to M
right you send the coordinator to the
blinded messages the blinded messages
are patters and commitments to M 1 and M
2 with randomness randomness is everyone
in there too so just by giving M 1 and M
2 the blinded messages to the
coordinator the coordinator will have no
clue whatsoever about message m1 and m2
but still we want to convince him that
the underlying committed messages adapt
to the public input to TXO value m and
it's super easy
due to the homomorphic property of
feathers and commitments so the comb the
coordinator would just
multiply and note this is multiplicative
notation hope people don't really don't
hate it so if we multiply these two
blinded messages then note that we would
have h2 em 1 plus em 2 multiplied with G
2 R 1 plus R 2 and if we give the sum of
the randomness values the coordinator
then the coordinator so basically we
open this the commitment corresponding
to the multiplication of the messages
then the and then the court and we could
we can convince the coordinator that
these values add up so this was like the
first step why we were kind of excited
about the blind be less signature
instantiated with the Patterson hash
because it gives us a really simple way
to prove splitting of UT exo's right
because if you want to make a payment
then it most likely you need to either
split or merge your UT axles but split
is the first thing we want it to solve
right yes so this is why we were started
to think about this be blind build a
signature scheme with the Patterson hash
and right let's let's continue or any
questions I just want to point out I
spoke earlier as in Bitcoin circles
usually people write in additive
notation and we wrote it here in
multiplicative notation but they're the
same thing
so that's the first clarification and
that second one is VLS signatures don't
work on bitcoins standard like elliptic
curve and it requires a different curve
which has what's called or different set
curse that has what's called a appearing
operation so I just thought that was
important yeah thank you please continue
ishtvan
i think it would be a good idea if you
guys explain stuff properly and then i
try to translate it to less technical
people and i think that that's a good
way to go about it so go ahead and
explain each one further okay so don't
get too much excited because this
protocol is broken but I can I can
explain it yeah what was the second
thought okay so now we know how to split
ut axis and let me just say it is not
broken it's it's something that you
don't like because you made a mistake
but the better double spending
protection actually fixes that mistakes
it's not actually broken yeah but it's
not lightweight it's not with it would
include additional assumptions like
you've uh pointed out so it builds upon
repairing base crypto and ideally we
would like to kind of remain at the same
technologies same assumptions but what
is already deployed in Bitcoin but
anyways let's continue so and how can we
prove so let's say we have we registered
a lots of input UT axis and now since we
not we also want to make payments
possibly potentially we might need to
consolidate some of our inputs right
because I don't know the payment value
is something super weird amount and and
we just need to merge coins so how to do
that with this blind be a signature
scheme with the Patterson hash so let's
say this is just an example of merging
to output to input UT exo's but
the same ideology would easily could be
easily generalized to multiple input UTX
emerging so let's say we have a mat
Hashem the message one and the signature
on a message one by the coordinator
since this is a blank signature scheme
the signature was not seen by the
coordinator yet as we have unlink
ability similarly we have the hash on
message two
and the signature on message 2 which
again was has not been seen by the
coordinator and now the question is how
can we prove that and we want to
register a UT EXO corresponding to the
value m1 plus m2 but we don't want to
reveal to the coordinator the underlying
value and bonding them too if this is a
cryptographic hash function which is
then so the coordinator doesn't see does
not know anything about message 1 and
our message 2 because this the Patterson
hash is the cryptographically secure
hash function given some range proofs
but let's put it aside so we just we
give the sum of the messages what we
want to register as an output to TX oh
well you and this for group element and
a small proof to convince the
coordinator that the underlying messages
adapt to this public value how can we do
that again we just need to it's super
simple we just need to multiply the
signatures what are the signatures the
signatures are now we just plug in the
definition here we just plug in the
definition of the blind a be a signature
scheme so Mac Sigma M 1 multiplied by
Sigma n 0 because the hash of the
message 1 raised to the coordinator
secret key multiplied with hash on the
message m 2 raised to the coordinators
secret key which is since in our case
the hash function is the Patterson hash
equals H 2 M 1x
and one is our secret value and the
other term is h2 m2x HSN generator in
the group so this equals H to X
multiplied with n plus and M 1 plus M 2
so the point is that if we give these
two values the coordinator then the
coordinator can just multiply them and
check this equality so note that this on
the right hand side H to the X
multiplied n plus M 1 plus M 2 can be
easily calculated by the coordinator so
access and the coordinators private key
and 1 and M 2 is the public values
because we this is the value of the
output UT X so we are registering so the
coordinator can compute this term and
similarly the coordinator can just
compute the multiplication of the two
signatures so the point here is that
this verification equality can be
trivially checked by the coordinator so
this is a super simple way to convince
the coordinator that look I have two
valid signatures on messages I'm not
going to tell you but still you can
verify that the underlying messages add
up to this public value so with that in
mind we basically solved on the problem
of splitting UT exo's and merging UT
exo's so basically the wabi-sabi is
ready right what do you think guys okay
so shall we kill the Joker or you want
to think about it by the way this is if
you go to Lobby subbies so github.com
/zk snags the slash wabi-sabi and the
fifth issue if you want to take it as a
homework or exercise to think about it
don't scroll that much down because here
you will see why it is broken but
yeah we were like in ecstasy in in half
a day and then through the reality hit
it yeah okay there are some subtleties
like we would need some padding scheme
but yeah okay
many questions comments on the on this
scheme okay so let's meet but what was
the problem with this and what was the
overcomplicated solution okay so so
let's give the protocol in two minutes
so the firm let's start with the obvious
mistake which was pointed out by Kobe
good cam good friend of mine so again
tech thanks cobby so the obvious problem
with this is that never ever so yeah
this is the description of blind BLS
signatures and anytime you would like to
implement it as a practitioner or or you
want to deploy it in the wild you need
to choose this hash function and one of
the key takeaways here is that you
should not choose blind be less
signatures with the Patterson hash
because then you you completely break
the underlying security properties of
the blank pls signature scheme why
because so this is the solution pointed
out by Coby
if a user has a single valid signature
so if the user has a message m and
obtains a blind signature which has the
form H to a max then a user can just
Forge any signature of her choice like
let's say M star and then can obtain a
valid blind signature on a message which
was not a very signed by the coordinator
so this is like conky
Italy breaks the guarantees the security
guarantees whatsoever of the blind build
a signature scheme so like so if you
learn something of this discussion so
far like first lesson is that don't
instantiate and blind be a signature
with but there's an - because then users
can screw you up yes and then and we
were trying to fix this protocol I'm not
sure if that's a little bit complicated
because then we would need to explain
what our accumulators but basically you
can save it but it's not
cryptographically sound construction and
protocol anymore because it would rely
on a completely broken blind signature
scheme so we were like well let's put
this aside and let's continue in another
direction because this is just not
kosher at all
yeah and that I think this is a good
point right to talk about trade-offs
because you know ultimately we want to
have a protocol that does communicate
with a central coordinator but we do not
want to have a decentralized protocol is
this would increase complexity it's also
staying centralized means we've reduced
complexity but then for example if we
would use this quote-unquote broken
protocol but fixed at both the
accumulators this would again increase
the complexity I then and this just
carries about a lot of trade-offs no of
just additional communication realms
where stuff can go wrong this is one of
the big ball next we haven't wasabi
currently that the torah' anonymity
network just breaks sometimes it does
not even work flawlessly all the time
and put the extra round of
communications this would become more
and more of an issue so so here again if
we can find a more beautiful
cryptographic solution that is less
complex that relies on less assumptions
and increment it then this would of
course be better so so that's why we
decided to abandon this approach and
look for something
and honestly there were many red flags
already from the beginning it's already
you well pointed out like obviously
blank signature sorry elliptic curve so
pairing based crypto is something
completely new and also we did some
research and we found out that there is
no C sharp implementation of BLS though
we as Max already pointed out like trade
offs so if we would have wanted to go
with the scheme then we would have
needed to implement our own BLS from
scratch so we also want to minimize
obviously the time to market so we would
like to make this available for our
users as soon as possible and and yeah
so yes all right thank you
just something here because I see we
have someone new and I just would like
to say hi Stefano would you like to
introduce yourself maybe all right can
you hear me yes yeah sorry I was a bit
late I missed the first part but I had
already seen the github issue so more or
less what you were talking about was not
completely new to me well about myself
master student at Alta when graduating
in July if everything goes right and I
have been interested in to block saying
Bitcoin in particular protocol since 2
to 3 years ago and yeah I'm pretty
passionate about cryptography I have
that's very maths so the mathematics
down there doesn't scare me anymore
oh I found it fun so I think I will take
part to this kind of meetings often in
the future I totally agree with that
I'm a bit sorry that I cannot help on
the implementation side because I'm not
really a c-sharp programmer it's
completely unknown to me but all right
let's continue and and I'm wondering how
shall we continue because because then
we went back maybe and with the idea
that maybe we can do something with our
feathers and commitments scheme but what
we had in mind and actually we brought a
comparison between our two schemes this
BLS signature scheme and our Patterson
commitment scheme and what we said is
the cryptography is for that Patterson
commitments scheme but which is
described in the beginning is relatively
simple the blind BLS signature scheme is
complex communication rounds the
Patterson commitment blind patterns and
commitment scheme does not introduce any
additional communication round while the
bind Els signature scheme does introduce
parallel communication round which means
it's not that bad this is because after
the input registration we have to give
out the accumulator for the two to the
piers so they can they can create their
outputs
and again coin splitting in the
Patterson commitments key in both scheme
is perfectly solved Cohen merging in the
Patterson commitment scheme is not
solved so there is privacy loss there in
the BLS signature scheme it's solved but
but again it could be improved by
introducing some denominations but we
really don't want to do that because we
are kind of back to back back to some
some some not very elegant scheme and
that's that's pretty much it and then we
went back and letters and commitments
came again and I would have a question
for the whole group I mean could you
maybe explain a bit more the the idea of
having um denominations and held know
how this would work and why this is not
optimal yeah sure so in the Patterson
committment scheme you can we we went
through how you can split the amounts
but we did not figure out how you can
match the amount so for example if you
have an input with one Bitcoin and
another input with two Bitcoin and then
you go with two different anonymity
Network identities and you you want a
three Bitcoin output then you wouldn't
be able to split any of those two inputs
to get three Bitcoin output but you
would somehow have to merge them and at
that point the only idea that we had in
mind that okay you get a Patterson
commitment for the one Bitcoin input and
Patterson commitment for the to Bitcoin
input and an adult with registration you
register them together so you are
basically exposing that you had a one
Bitcoin you have one Bitcoin and you
have three Bitcoin and where where can
those come from probably from the one
Bitcoin impotent probably from the three
Bitcoin input so that's not idea for
this we can introduce denominations that
just create a bunch of standard letters
and commitments than letters and
commitments with standard amounts and in
that way the coordinator at least I
thought would registration it will be
quiet quite difficult for the
coordinator to tell well often
impossible the where those are coming
from and that could work but but again
like introducing thousands of brothers
and commitments and things like this is
not very elegant and probably we would
just end up having implementation issues
all over the place
so what s can we do with this and each
twin spent some time on it at home and
he came up with something which I cannot
claim to understand but then we
progressed a bit further and and I'm not
okay so do you guys want to chime in
maybe you are better equipped to explain
our further progress here I think the
next thing we should like if we go over
issue number 10 I think we should have
enough time to cover it based on what we
already did it's quite similar because
it also uses by linear groups the
Patterson commitments are similar but
the signature algorithm and the
verification equation are different and
it
introduces some problems but it also
solved some problems and I think that
that's a good direction to to go in for
today do you present to everyone like
when when your screen sharing and
somebody else is talking then like I
think would still be useful to have your
screen show so you can click on each one
and it that way his monitor is going to
be be the dominant on your computer even
if you are talking I'm going to do that
too so the recording will be will be
correct yeah for the recording thank you
well I'm not sure how much time we want
to spend with this because this ad so
because this is not something super
known signature scheme so can I ask one
more question about last topic please
please do like if I understood correctly
whenever you are getting the outputs
from the coin zone you have to have at
least two outputs am I wrong or is it
that you have to have at least the same
amount of outputs coming out as you put
in in inputs more we want to make make
it be completely arbitrary III mean we
will have some restrictions some
standard amounts and things like that at
upper layers but on this layer were we
are working right now we want appears to
register completely arbitrary amounts
and number of inputs and completely
arbitrary amounts and number of outputs
later we will restrict it but for now we
want to to build something that's
flexible and at up early layers we will
restrict them
the short answer would be that there is
no correlation between the number of
input UT X's and the number of how to do
T X's they don't necessarily need to be
equal the only thing which is necessary
that roughly the sum of the input UT X's
equals and some of the output beauty X
values minus Fe and does this answer the
question yeah exactly that but what was
the problem with BLS and Peterson
signature wasn't it like that you can't
like just have one output coming out if
you are putting two inputs so the
problem is that again just to refresh so
this this was the blind build a
signature scheme like put this into your
photographic memory and then if so you
need to choose here a hash function you
see like you need to choose something
you need to go with a particular hash
function and if it if this particular
hash function is the peterson hash which
is basically takes a random generator in
the group let's say h and raise it to H
to the M so if that this is how you
define your hash function right so H of
M let's define it as H to the N mod P P
is a prime number which is the order of
the group so the number of elements in
the group then you will have a hash
function but the problem is that with
this instantiation the signature scheme
is completely broken so it's kind of
really non-intuitive because you would
you would just thought you one might
just think that okay I take the blind be
a signature scheme I instantiate it with
whatever hash function and then it
should be alright right this is like
what I thought but it turns out not to
be true so okay yeah yeah I get that and
that was understandable my question was
a little bit wrong I'm new with these
terms so bear with me
but learning
yeah maybe what I actually meant was the
problem with having multiple outputs and
merging them into one output I mean what
was the problem in that was it because
that so the problem that just cannot
have one output no no you can't have the
problem is that when you want to do this
you don't want to tell the coordinator
what are the values you are merging
because then the coordinator might guess
from which input UT axis you are trying
to merge and then you would leak you
would lose some privacy against the
coordinator does this answer the
question oh yeah exactly so let's let's
say you have two input UT axis like I
don't know 0.1 0.2 and you want to
register an output you TXO with value
0.3 then you want to do this in a way
that you don't want to tell the
coordinator then now pay coordinator now
I'm merging 0.1 you tx1 0.2 because then
the coordinator might guess okay this is
raffia this is because yeah so this is
what we want to avoid and to put this a
little bit more formal you want to
convince the coordinator that you have
valid signatures on messages that you
don't want to tell them because usually
if you verify messages as digital
signatures then in the verification
algorithm you also put the message
itself as an input right but if in this
case you would put them messages and
input in the verification algorithm then
you would lose privacy or some privacy
and and we need to come up with a way to
verify messages digital signatures
without giving out the underlying
message that that's the cryptographic
challenge here okay
yeah thanks that explained it yeah
so basically this is the challenge of
the main challenge of wabi-sabi of this
protocol
today thanks to your value is we have a
pretty neat solution which is I think
the most lightweight but not sure if we
will be able to cover it tonight yeah we
have basically two more protocols left
right do you do you want to go through
your your protocol that that that you
came up based on the knowledge
assumption paper or or go right to the
to the to the last one yeah maybe gold
right the next next one I can wrap it up
in five minutes so like it was kind of
obvious we motivated a thousand times we
love others and commitments because it's
homomorphic so we were looking for blind
signature scheme which allows us to have
a blind signature on a message committed
in a Patterson commitment and apparently
there are two schemes achieving this
this paper and another one by Foxborough
at all but it's a little bit more
complicated and then we were playing
around with this scheme wait a sec and I
can show you yeah this is the blind
signature scheme which I suppose in the
group only one or two people know but
don't worry this is not that well-known
paper yet and and then we created some
proof mechanism which allows us to do
utx so merging so splitting is basically
given for free because these blind
signature schemes gives us blind
signatures on committed messages on
patters and commitments like here this
is additive notation somewhat different
than the previous notation don't get
intimidated so basically here this is
the message which is committed in the
Patterson commitment and at the end of
the day we will have a blank signature
on this message without the court
letting the coordinator know what she
was signing so we have input UT access
splitting for free
and then we were creating some zero
knowledge proof systems to allow us to
do the merging but I don't think it's
that important because it's a little bit
would be too long and I don't want to
waste your time you can see all the
discussion here on blind things on
Patterson commitments hashtag ten number
ten yeah here's the protocol which
achieves this merging yeah maybe I think
it would be more enlightening if you
would hear the easiest way to do it all
right let's do that let's let's do that
first on what could you go on the the
issue yes please share your screen
because I cannot because that doesn't
get recorded very social issue that I
created and and after that you've uh but
let's first go through on mine double
blind is competitors income cool right
so I I want to go through this because
this might be easier to understand and
you was is is something that that's very
similar to this we kind of came up with
it in parallel I mean I can't really
claim that I came up with anything
because I was just coming up with
desires that it would be cool if the
crypto would work this way but anyway so
yeah yeah go go go back yeah so the idea
was that what if instead of we blind the
patterns and commitments once we could
blind them twice wow that would be
really cool wouldn't it so okay we blind
them twice and in that way we would get
the signatures for the single brightness
commitments and not the double blinded
and those single-blind that commitments
could be registered together later on
because a and and and the some could be
proven easily and because no one has
seen because the coordinator did not see
those singer blinded commitments and we
have signatures on them it can accept
their some and we don't actually expose
the amounts so this was my idea and you
will had a better one based on the the
paper that we actually looked through
last three search clubs so that didn't
go to waste and I would like to give yes
do you have any anything to add to my
really incomplete conceptual explanation
or or go through you guys stuff which
which seems be a more fine now I don't
know let's see so do you have anything
to add to this so far or give the word
to you but no let's let's give the word
to you well okay so I guess can you open
issue sixteen I guess the first thing is
we should give some credit for this idea
of double blinding the commitments and
that comes from paper relating to Z
Coyne lalangue tus I think it's cool
and the idea there is you kind of it's
not a signature based approach but
there's a lot of similarities and you
use other people's like every coin is
basically a Patterson commitment to an
amount so the amounts are confidential
like confidential transactions and then
you take additional coins as like decoy
inputs
and you kind of prove that you only
spent yours in the output creation but
this kind of where we got this double
binding concept I think it's I would
prefer if we refer to those as like
unlink of all commitments just because
double binding I think means something
specific in in that article so a similar
thing is instead of blinding instead of
taking a Patterson commitment blinding
it and receiving a signature on like the
unblinded version the anonymous
credentials light signature scheme does
something a little bit different where
you you give just North Edison
commitment and in the anonymous
credentials work the the thing that
you're actually signing there is what
like that's what they call an attribute
of the credential so in this signature
scheme the the user commits to a list of
attributes as a Patterson multi
commitment and then has a protocol to
get a signature not on that commitment
but a different commitment a blinded
commitment that still commits to the
same values so it's practically the same
thing
instead of like blinding getting a
signature and unblinding you provide
like one commitment and you get back a
signature for a differently blinded
commitment to the same messages and I
think probably we don't want to go into
too much detail about how the the
protocol actually works
it took me literally hours to just get
through one page of the paper and I
still don't think I understand
everything so I think like that is a
reasonable summary of of what what that
construction actually gives us
and then we can sort of recover the nice
properties of the second protocol that
we didn't discuss in too much detail
so unlike the the BLS signatures the
signatures are not homomorphic so but
the commitments are so we can still have
splitting we can make a series of
commitments to the split amounts that we
want they remain hidden and then we
receive we prove that the sum of these
commitments is equal to our input amount
and then we receive a list of signatures
on different commitments for the same
amount and those signatures don't have
like the double spending issues that we
we ran into with some of the merging
stuff or the signature forging so at
output registration time I just reveal
those signatures and each signature is
like a token but because the
verification equation for this signature
scheme works on the commitment not on
the message instead of giving the sub
amounts that we're like let's say I I
have two inputs and I want to take like
some I sorry I want to split my first
input and I want to split my second ad
but and then I want to take two sums out
of those for some reason at output
registration I provide two signatures
and two pettersen commitments for the
split amounts but I only need to reveal
the sum I don't actually reveal the
message at signature verification time
so this gives us a slightly easier to
reason about way of proving to the
coordinator that we're not overspending
in our output registration without
actually revealing the sub amounts that
we we only reveal the sounds um I think
that's a fair summary
I guess does anybody have any questions
at this point and if like we want to go
into more detail I can make maybe
explain a little bit more about the
signature algorithm itself thank you I
think we can actually leave this for the
next session to go into details in this
while obviously if if we we don't find
something is terribly wrong with this
and then we have to start all over again
if we find something terribly broken
then we I think we have an even better
reason to to do a research club bonnet
it was solid if it was solidified the
next for the for next week then then we
are go through it if it won't that's it
that's something to add about the
signature scheme an attractive property
is that it does not require bilinear
groups it's still Jana said last week
that some parts of the security proof
rely on so like you for a curve with say
128-bit security like set P 256 K one
you actually get a slightly reduced
security level I have not yet gotten to
those parts so I don't know if this is
an issue for us but at least in
principle if that's not a concern for
the soundness of the the protocol and
the the privacy of the protocol actually
the privacy is much more important if
that's not a concern then that means
that we can just use the same curve as
Bitcoin which has some nice advantages
as well
all right so was everything clear no yes
I mean I only have some new questions so
I'll maybe leave them to the end and
give other guy's a chance to ask I've
never heard this concept of double
lining or you know double and Patterson
commitments
yes exactly what's my question it like
do we have some peer reviewed like
proofs that this is sound or which is
hoping here paper was showing the double
blinding Patterson commitments but but
but he was but but the ACL paper idea is
actually not reliant on these doesn't
use double blinding it's what what does
it use what would you say that I think
it's a slightly technical but the idea
is so okay first I don't remember the
exact details of the double blinding but
from a security point of view there's no
there's no problem really because you
it's just like adding another factor to
the one of the generator points so you
can think of it as taking a Patterson
commitment and I think multiplying it by
a scalar that's no different than what
you do in a normal Patterson commitment
it's just like the the way that the
Lanza's paper uses it is the second
blinding is like a serial number and if
you and that's used for the way that
like Z coin does a double spend
prevention or like makes marks a coin
spent basically
so since our scheme is online we don't
actually need that and what we have in
the ACL scheme is a sort of similar
approach where you start with a
commitment and then in the signature
protocol eventually you get a signature
on another commitment that's multiplied
by a different scalar so actually I'm
not sure if it's a scalar and I'm not
gonna check just now because but like
think of it as like adding another key
like tweaking a key if you're familiar
with that terminology you're just taking
a curve point and adding like more like
another point to it and because of like
the reasons that a Pettersen commitment
works out as like a secure system this
you know generalizes to repeated
transformations like that if that did
not hold then like the Paterson
commitments themselves would not work so
I think that double blinding term is a
little bit scary but really all it means
is like firstly blind it and then you
blind it some more so in the ACL scheme
that process like in the the Lantis
stuff you you first you you do that
blinding and then you you blind some
more and then you prove something to the
blockchain about the like the the
composition of these in the ACL scheme
you start by blinding the amount once in
a like a normal Paterson commitment and
in the end you get a signature for a
different Paterson commitment that has
like additional blinding applied to it
but still commits the same thing so it's
kind of the same effect you there's no
way to link the two commitments because
the user controls the randomness going
into the the derived commitment but
the underlying messages are still the
same and the ACL protocol basically
guarantees that you can only get a
signature that commits to the the same
stuff that you made a commitment to at
the beginning of the protocol did that
explain it a bit better yeah the double
blinding thing was now a bit more clear
but yeah I think I have to just check
this show again after it's published
so I get everything out of this I mean
this ACL thing is still a bit confusing
but I don't think it's I just need some
time to process it but yeah thanks for
all the explanations I have a question I
don't really know if it makes sense at
all and it's on a higher level so is
there any interest or do we see any
particular problems in willing to output
from such coin join an output which is
multi signature in some way so it's a
double question does it even make sense
to think about it is there any use cases
for it and is it technically thinkable
with the within this scheme yes and yes
I think there are many interesting use
cases for multi signatures I'm not sure
if no power agrees but
did all of this stuff is only concerned
with the amounts of the outputs not the
scripts themselves so when you go to
register and output if you want all the
script types to be the same the
coordinator can just say you know when
you register and output you must provide
a pay to pop key hash output or
something like that or it it could let
you put any script type that you want
but the the cryptographic commitments
that we discussed so far are only
concerned with the satoshi amount that
that output will get not with the script
pub key
you could even register nope return so
yeah so and further maybe public key
tweaking to make it more efficient you
know the maybe the only thing that I
that could be an issue here is that you
want to give a maximum size for this
script that may be smaller than then
what Bitcoin would then what the Bitcoin
standards are because you don't know who
is paying for the for the script so that
input registration you you have to take
the network fees from people and and
let's see if everyone would come with
the maximum script sized script that
would be a denial of service attack or
things like that gets to there because
if the coordinator produces a
non-standard transaction then it's not
gonna get relayed but the beta script
hash completely gets around this problem
because the script pop key only contains
the hash of the script and there's no
standard Ness rules restricting redeem
scripts so unless you want to do like a
raw multi-sig screen
pop key or something like that I I don't
think that's really an issue yeah I was
thinking more about well it's not there
yet but I was thinking more about
Shannara multi signatures so that
wouldn't be so if we get tap script
outputs or the set with v1 outputs
they're gonna be even simpler then
because you're only really gonna have
one script type it's always going to be
32 bytes and it's functionally
equivalent to a paid to puppy hash and a
pay the script hash at the same time so
you can always after like as part of the
input of the next spending transaction
you can provide a tap script that
redeems it or you can sign with the I
forget what it's called that the key at
the the root and that would be I mean
it's not a pop key hash but it's like
paid a pub key so in this regard
if tap root is enabled and we also have
snore signatures in in the same go then
like the there's only going to be one
script type that's relevant for said
with v1 outputs yes so we probably have
to restrict arbitrary non standard
script some of return output as far as
size is concerned but but any script
that someone can imagine because because
of the PTO's script hash shesh script
hash kind of constructions which are
actually the standard way of doing
things so you can you can do almost
anything except non-standard stuff so
maybe a trivial example but or trivial
use case I was thinking
whether it was possible to have a
[Music]
lightning tunnel creation as a output
from coin join round so since that's the
weakest point in the in the privacy of
lightning you have public keys
associated publicly to some multi
signature transaction which is the
funding transaction it would be nice to
be able to provide privacy while going
in into the protocol so it's not
possible to trace back coins the history
of coins that create a fund a
transaction transaction so this is
something I've thought about quite a bit
already today you can do this with
single funded channels and join market
and there's no technical reason
whatsoever why this should not be
possible in wasabi that's just a
question of the transaction structure
that's currently enforced that requires
pay to witness pub key hash outputs I
think that in this protocol that we're
proposing that's not going to be any
different it's up to the coordinator
policy to interesting things to consider
about this are it's not just that so
like coin joints can help lightening
privacy but lightning can also break
coin joint privacy because the outputs
are announced on like the the lightning
graph the the gossip protocol so like
every node that has public channels has
a stable identifier its node ID and it's
basically linking a bunch of multi-sig
outputs that it's involved in
so I still think it's probably a good
idea but there's some really tricky
interactions to consider there and it
may turn out to be less desirable than
it seems at first and it's a little bit
more interesting with dual funded
channels so there's in the last few
months I think Lisa negged wrote a
proposal for interactive channel opening
that allows dual funding and prior to
that I think it's a generalization of a
prior work that is meant to deal with
splicing which i think is also very
interesting to consider in the context
of coin joints I think that the main
advantage that you gain is if you want
to open a channel to some other node and
you don't want to disclose how many
funds you had in a prior YouTube so that
you used to fund this then you get a
considerable benefit from coin joining
this and that's already possible today
with sea lightnings like API and
something like join markets patience and
just one actually had wrote a paper
previously so I would love to hear his
input here to know sorry for
interrupting you but I feel this was a
really nice example on how like
non-trivial ways some can reduce the
Hana limited set because like when
Stefano was asking the question I was
like wow this is a nice idea but then I
realized that if for example in today's
if you go to graph dot L in the Explorer
comm slash API slash graph you can
actually have a look at all the nodes
consisting of the public public graph
and you can investigate it essentially
like less than 1% of all the
would use tor and which means that the
rest of the 99% of the nodes exposes
their IP addresses so essentially if you
would use if you would do this like
Cohen joined out to a funding
transaction then you would instantly
lose one guy from the coin joint because
most likely that guy will just use
lightning with IP addresses and then you
would instantly know that this guy lives
in I don't know Chicago or something
like that so yeah this was a really nice
point from Nevada and great insight and
not only that one output but all of
their other channels as well yeah I mean
they're lightning as a lot of privacy
potential but currently it's just so
up Ted eventually will probably
have to do it in wasabi to be privacy
focused but in general I think this is a
very promising idea to do Kong joins
into good Lightning openings they're
lighting channel openings and especially
into something like lightning channel
factories or maybe Hyperloop Atomics box
into or out of the Lightning Network so
I think there's a lot of huge promise
here very long term because right now
the Lightning Network simply it's not
hit there you see the philosophy that I
changed from when I when I was writing
zero linking in C rolling I wanted to
ensure standard behavior from an
everyone who is who is mixing but now
here is I don't want anymore I want to
ensure as much flexibility as possible
and the clients has to work in a
standard way until one or two client
wants to to work in a different way like
he wants to open a
channel let's say and and you know if
it's easy to put the cut in to the
microwave accidentally if you are
behaving differently from other people
but in this case from how we are working
on here is that if you are actively if
you actively want to do something then I
don't want to prevent it anymore that
the only point the only goal is to most
of the the peers are are using the
default stuff and not messing around
with with with different parameters so
so yeah that let's not prevent things
but make sure that most of the peers are
using the default parameters so so
anonymity is and isn't terribly
compromised if if some someone wants to
to create scripts all the time or open
lightning channels all the time things
like that that that's what I I want to
do differently in this case if we want
to really philosophize then a long term
like think of the just a thought
experiment but if every coin join
instead of having multiple inputs and
multiple outputs had only a lot of
inputs going - a giant multi-sig for
everybody and a multi-sig coming out of
that and the coin join theft prevention
security worked by exactly like
lightning funding so you don't sign the
first transaction until everybody else
has signed to the output transaction
this is all really silly right you you
gain no benefit
it's now it's two transactions and the
interaction of a multi-sig is probably a
catastrophe but what you get out of it
is something that's very similar to a
multi-party payment channel and I think
like a very interesting long-term I mean
this requires soft Forks and all sorts
of novel like technology but it would be
really cool if the anonymity set of coin
joint type transactions was not just a
moment in time right where people could
sort of come into a pool and leave at
some later point much like a multi-party
payment channel so that anyway I just
think this is a fascinating idea and
something I've been thinking a lot about
how maybe one day we get it but it's all
very you know just in the future stuff
it's like similar I think but so I think
the Lightning privacy model I think is
fantastic for payments it's terrible for
coin history's so like what you
basically announced to the world is
here's how much money I have and then at
some later point you announced to the
world this is how much I have now
whenever you fund or close channels and
you don't disclose you know the the
transactions that you did in the middle
and this is exactly the opposite of the
kind of privacy that coin joins give
which is like you completely obscure the
history or not completely but you you
obscure the history to a reasonable
amount but then people can still see the
net flow on the pay drawing ideas they
kind of break that assumption but in in
principle you could you know continue
that
in a much more general direction where I
think payment channels coin giant
transactions page oint type interactions
things like covenants all of these
things go together in a way that's
beneficial for privacy it's because
privacy because fringe ability is
emergent from privacy it's beneficial
for the network as a whole and it's also
I think great for scaling because
effectively you use coin joins it's like
just a batch transaction mechanism so
you can think of like the the logical
end state of this is every like you have
blocks just filled with giant coin joint
transactions which basically are
snapshots of of channel states and
people just move in and out of channel
states and the most of the the actual
activity is off chain there's some
issues with that which is you know what
happens if people stop cooperating and
then your block size is too limited and
some people can't exit so still not
straightforward but I I think the
general intuition of putting is little
information on the blockchain itself
about what sort of interactions people
actually have like what actual payments
they send to each other that has
benefits for scaling for privacy and
fungibility so I would really like to
see all these things converge long term
anyway this is really off topic I'm
sorry so one of the most interesting
ideas there is up CTV up the cheque
template verify that's Jeremy Reubens
covenants construction and there's some
really cool stuff that he demonstrates
like his proofs of concept for things
like congestion control transactions I
think that that's the most interesting
direction that this stuff can go in and
with something slightly more general
than what he proposed like we could get
some really awesome stuff
closing the conversation and I hope
everyone enjoyed this cryptography
lesson this one and half an hour
cryptography lesson and now you can go
to your universities and tell them that
you applied what you learned there and
okay thank you guys
next week we are not going to have a
topic but the topic is going to be that
wabi-sabi repository whatever will
happen there I don't know
as you can see we have two guys working
on it who are much much smarter than
then and you know I know it's extreme
being brain power is on that repository
so we will see that what what's going to
happen next week what we are going to
talk about and that's it thank you for
for watching like share and subscribe
contribute to to between privacy and see
you next week bye bye
I think I died right